

954.825.6249

Pompano Beach/FL/USA

Zoom Availability

% http://datascientistbrain.top

cad9179/CarlosDiazGithub

## ABOUT ME

Data Analyst with experience in interpreting and analyzing data for driving business solutions. Proficient knowledge in statistics, mathematics, visualizations, and sales. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analyses of data. Bilingual in English and Spanish with basic understanding of Italian and Portuguese. Motivated, team-work oriented and responsible.

# EDUCATION

- Associates of Business Administration (A.A)-Miami Dade College. 1997
- ✓ Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A)Kennesaw State College. 2010
- ✓ Master of Business (M.B.A) Business Intelligence- Nova Southeastern — (Summer 2021) (1 class left)
- ✓ Associates of Business Intelligence (A.A.S)-Miami Dade College. 2019
- ✓ Bachelor of Science (B.S) Data Analytics-Miami Dade College. Expected Graduation (May 21) (1 class left)

# CERTIFICATIONS

- ✓ Python for everybody 2020
- ✓ Business Intelligence Certification 2019
- ✓ Machine Learning Foundations 2021
- ✓ Big data Specialization 2021

## EXPERIENCE

#### **Data Analyst**

MTTH Group \ Pompano Beach \ April 2020 to present (Remotely)

Interpreting data, analyzing results using statistical techniques and present to Owners. Developed and implemented data analyses, data collection systems to optimize accounting operations. Manage data warehouse and maintaining Website databases. Create ad hoc reports as needed using tableau.

### **Data Analyst**

Carrier Enterprise \ Pompano Beach \ Jan 2019-April 2020

Evaluated marketing trends and predictions and researching market conditions to develop sales goals, marketing strategies and forecasting using Python. Analyzed team territories and monitored sales programs using Excel, T-SQL, Tableau and Power-BI. Used Hadoop for handling Tera data with Spark.

### **Data Analyst**

Trane Supply \ Pompano Beach \ Feb 2015- Mar 2019

Prepared Tableau dashboards and sales analysis using Excel, Power-Bi and SSRS. Used Pandas and Numpy to organize data and present on Tableau. Maintained data Warehouse in SQL and SSIS.

## KEY SKILLS

Python, Django, C++, R, SQL (SSRS, SSIS, SSRS, SSAS), ETL, NoSQL, Snowflake, AWS, MongoDB. Salesforce. Big Data (Hadoop, Hive, Yarn), API, GIT, Spark. Pandas, Pytorch. Tableau, Azure, Informatica, SAS, Machine Learning(scikit-learn), A/B tests, Algorithms, Matplolib, Cloud-based data analysis and Integration. Google analytics. Jupyter Notebook.